It's not always going to be great.
There's a new AI image editor that is
blowing everybody's minds right now. You
can pretty much give it an image, tell
it to change that image in any way you
want, and it's doing a way better job
than even what GPT40 was doing. Remember
when all the Studio Giblly stuff was
going crazy? Yeah, this one seems even
better than that. This could potentially
even be a full-on replacement for
Photoshop. You give it an image. You
tell it what you want changed about the
image and it makes those changes and it
actually looks good. This thing is like
the hottest thing on Twitter and Reddit
right now.
So hot right now
and I don't want to waste your time. So
let's take a peek at what I'm talking
about. The model goes by the code name
Nano Banana. And it's not technically
released or available publicly yet. In
fact, no company has even claimed it's
their model yet. Rumor has it that it's
a new model out of Google, but I can't
confirm that. This person claims here
that you could find it in Google Studio,
leading a lot of people to believe that
it's Google, but as of right now, it's
not in my Google AI studio. So, I don't
know. Maybe they've got an early access
or something. But let's take a peek at
some of what other people have created
with this model cuz it's pretty
mind-blowing what you can do. And then I
will show you a workaround so that you
could go and use it right now if you
want. It's a little wonky, but you can
actually go and demo Nano Banana and you
can do it for free. Let's take a look at
some of these images from D Studio
project. Here we can see this was the
original base image. They claim they
generated this original image in
midjourney, but then here's their edits.
So, shot one, make them sitting on the
billiard table. So, you can see it put
them sitting on a billiard table. And if
you look at the faces, it looks like the
same faces. It looks like the same
outfits. Everything crosses over for
shot two. You can see that they actually
used shot one as their image prompt.
They used this image here as the initial
image and they gave it the prompt make
them now playing billiards. One girl
wants to shoot the ball. Another one is
standing waiting her turn. And you can
see the women look consistent. The
outfits look consistent. There's some
wonkiness on the pool table. I don't
know why there's a pool queue there and
the sort of rack there, but it kept the
look consistent, the characters
consistent, the outfits consistent, even
the environment consistent where you can
see there's a pool table here in this
orientation and then one in the
background in this orientation with
these lamps. Everything is consistent
between the two different images. Here's
another base image that they started
with. Prompt, make them holding cocktail
glasses. Now, you can see it's the same
three women in the same exact
environment, all holding cocktail
glasses. Change the girl in the middle
to become a man like Tony Stark. Iron
Man and they hug him. And you can see
they put an Iron Man Tony Stark. Another
example, change the lantern to a
shotgun. She's no longer holding the
lantern. She is holding a gun. Don't
know if that really looks like a
shotgun, but she is holding a gun. And
then in shot two, the woman is no longer
inside the barn. Place her outdoor
sitting under a large tree in a forest
clearing. She is holding the shotgun
across her lap, carefully reloading
shells into it with focused
determination. But this is just
scratching the surface. Here's some more
examples from Cheda Slooa. We could see
two images here that clearly look like
the exact same person in the same room,
just different outfits and with glasses
on one of them. Diego here found that
you can do a really good job at
colorizing images using this new Nano
Banana model. Here's an original black
and white photo. It's also got some like
blurriness and some weird out of focus
stuff and it just isn't a great quality
image. And then when we take a peek at
what Nano Banana did to it, everything
kind of comes more clear. It added
colors. Everything looks really, really
good. I didn't even realize that this
was a girl holding a balloon until I saw
the nano banana image with color and I
can make out what was going on. Here's
another one of some ladies that look
like they're standing out in like a corn
field. And here's the colorized version.
Here's an older image that looks a
little out of focus and just sort of
dated with some extra little like dust
or noise in the image here. And here's a
cleaned up version that Nano Banana did.
Crystal here used it to change the text
on a billboard. She gave it like a
billboard from Times Square or
something. This was the original
billboard. She gave it the prompt change
the billboard's words to, "Hi, I'm
Crystal. I need more followers. Please
follow my thing." And then her at name
and then Christa Inc. And we can see the
one on the left here is what Nano Banana
generated. It filled in the text
perfectly and replaced the original
banner with her text. Flux one context
was also able to do it pretty well, but
we can see that Nano Banana is capable
of it. My friend Heather Cooper showed
off that you can actually use it to
blend two images together. She gave it
these two photos that you can see up in
the top right. This is Heather Cooper on
the right here. I believe this is an AI
generated image on the left. Not 100%
sure. Add the woman wearing sunglasses
to the first picture behind the first
woman as she shops and looks at clothes
on the shopping rack side profile and
you can see side by side. Here's what
Nano Banana generated. This looks just
like Heather Cooper in the background
and then the woman from this photo here
is in the forefront. I found this really
interesting as well. HBT here says they
believe that Nano Banana makes 3D
objects in terms of volume and then
edits inside of that space. They show
off in their images here that it was
able to successfully put a grid just
over the subject of this image. Here's
another example where it put a skeleton
within that grid. And here's another one
where you can see the skeleton in the
grid sort of better overlaid over the
original image. But they're basically
saying that they believe that this model
is looking at the image, sort of mapping
it out in 3D space to understand what's
going on in the image and then just
tweaking the elements within the grid
areas of what they want changed, which
is really interesting. Now, I can't
confirm this is how the model works. I
will be talking to some people at the
company that created this model pretty
soon and get you more details on that.
Have you ever wondered exactly which AI
tools, strategies, and ROI frameworks
the fastest growing startups are using
right now? Most founders are left
guessing, but my audience is getting
something nobody else has yet. Thanks to
HubSpot for startups, you're getting
exclusive early access to part two of
their AI at go to market report 2025.
Part one is already public, but part two
isn't even out yet, and you're seeing it
before anyone else. This section is
packed with HubSpot's exclusive analysis
of over 500 venture-backed startups
revealing the exact AI tools,
implementation strategies, and ROI
frameworks driving measurable go-to
market results. It's not theory. It's
actionable realworld insight you can
apply today. You'll see how top
performing startups structure their AI
teams, where they're getting their
biggest ROI, and how they're scaling
faster than ever. sometimes hitting
hund00 million ARR numbers with under
150 employees. So, if you're serious
about growth in 2025, grab this
exclusive early access now through the
link in the description and use it to
benchmark your strategy against the
best. Thanks so much to HubSpot for
Startups for sponsoring today's video.
Now, let's get back to it. Now, I
mentioned there's a way to use it for
free, but it is kind of wonky. And
before I get into it, I do want to tell
you you should probably be very, very
careful. There are websites out there
claiming that they're nano banana. I
even saw one that I think was at
nanoanana.ai
claiming that they're using this model.
They're not. It's not available yet. The
API is not available yet. They're lying
to you. As far as I know, the only way
to use this model is over on LMA, which
you can find by going to lmarena.ai.
If you're not familiar with LMA,
basically it's a blind test leaderboard
website. You give it a prompt. It gives
you two responses from that prompt
without telling you what model just gave
you those two responses. You pick
whether you like model A or model B
best. And that is how the rankings on
this leaderboard works. And they test
pretty much everything. They've got a
leaderboard for text models. Which ones
generate text the best? There's a webdev
for coding models. And they also have
image edit which is what we're talking
about right now. As you can see, the
number one model is GPT Image 1. No
mention of Nano Banana anywhere in this
list, and that's because it's still in
its initial testing phase, and they're
still collecting data before they can
finally rank it on the leaderboard. So,
you're probably already starting to see
where this is going. You can use Nano
Banana, but it's going to come in one of
those blind taste test prompts, right?
So, if you're on Ella Marina and you
come up to the top left and click on new
chat and then under direct chat here,
you have some options. Battle, side by
side, and direct chat. If we go to
direct chat and I turn on generate
images, you'll see that it gives me a
drop down of image models that I can
play with. Cool little life hack here.
You can use all of these images for free
right now in Ella Marina, but no Nano
Banana. They do have this sideby-side
comparison. This is designed to compare
two models next to each other, but once
again, Nano Banana isn't available here.
They only made it available currently in
the blind testing, which is why I said
it's a little wonky. So, the final
option here is the battle option. You
don't get to pick which models you use.
It picks two, and you have something
like a 20% chance that one of them is
going to be nano banana. saying that
because this is free to use, you can
keep on generating until you get the
image model that you actually want. Now,
in order to make sure it's going to do
an image edit and not do a text
response, you do need to make sure
generate images is turned on so it knows
to use the image models. And then you're
going to give it an image to edit. So,
I'm going to drop in this image that we
made last week with the Mountain Dew
River, pizza buildings, and Dorito
Mountains. We'll toss it in right here
and we'll give it a prompt like add a
surfer riding on the river. We'll submit
it and you'll see it's actually
generating two images, but it's not
telling us which model each image is. We
then get both options back and we have
to choose left is better, right is
better, both are bad, or it's a tie. I
would say both of these are pretty good
here. I feel like I like write a little
bit better because I feel like it
matches the style of the rest of the
image a little bit better. So, I'll say
right is better. And the funny thing is
we actually got Nano Banana on the very
first try. I just picked the one on the
right was better, which was Quinn
imageEdit, which is the other image
editing model that just came out that is
sort of blowing people's minds. They're
both really, really good. But, as you
can see, we got an image out of Nano
Banana right here on the left. It added
our surfer into the image. And we did
this without needing Photoshop. It did
exactly what it was supposed to. If I
toss the same image back in and say make
it nighttime, we could submit that. And
we'll be real lucky if we get Nano
Banana again the second time. Here's our
two images. The left is almost too dark.
It's hard to see. The right looks like
dark nighttime, but with some lights on
in the buildings, it knew to turn on the
lights. So, I would definitely say right
is better. And this one was nano banana.
So, as you can see, I mean, it's fairly
decent odds that you're going to get
nano banana when you're doing image
edits. And if you don't get nano banana,
you just throw the image in, throw your
prompt in again, and you do it again
until you actually get the model you
want. Or, you know, worst case scenario,
maybe you don't get nano banana, but you
get the edit that you wanted. It just
came from a different model. LM Marina
is really awesome and really powerful
because not only can you use it for free
and use almost any large language model
you want, use any image generator that's
in there, use all the image editors that
are in there, do it all completely for
free, but you're also helping contribute
to the AI community and helping them
understand which models are currently
the best by user standards. I've got
this image here of a vampire and a wolf.
Let's see if I can actually inject
myself into this image in some way. So,
we'll go ahead and pull this image in.
Do Ella Marina here. And then I'm going
to pull in a head shot. Just drag this
one in as well. And you can see we've
got two images. Add the man in the plaid
shirt standing behind the wolf and the
vampire. Let's see how well it does at
sort of blending these images together.
Again, the initial result may not be a
nano banana result. All right, we got
two back. Neither look great at all.
This one was really horrible at
following instructions. The one on the
left put a man behind everything, but it
doesn't really look like the same
person. I would definitely say left is
better. And this was seated 3.0 and this
one was Gemini 2.0 Flash preview. So, we
didn't get Nano Banana, which makes
sense because, well, neither of them
were great. And well, it took me a few
more tries with some weird ones. I feel
like Quinn imageedit did a pretty decent
job. I feel like it made me kind of look
like John Wick a little bit, but it did
a pretty good job. And then down here,
when I finally got Nano Banana, here's
what it did. It just made it look like a
very bad Photoshop edit. But I did
eventually get Nano Banana and this was
my result. So, just like any other AI
image generator, it's not always going
to be great. Another thing I want to
try, I actually saw Matt Vid Pro do this
in a video. He said it's really good at
generating YouTube thumbnails. So, I
actually want to take this Mountain Dew
image here. Let's go ahead and just copy
the image, post it back into our prompt
box. Also, take my headsh shot, toss
this in here, and say make a YouTube
thumbnail about the Mountain Dew River.
And then I'll give it those two images
and see if we can actually get it to
generate something that looks like a
decent thumbnail. Here's what it
generated. I mean, it's not horrible,
but it's not the proper aspect ratio.
But it did incorporate both images, the
Mountain Dew image, my face, added some
text, the legend of the Mountain Dew
River. Even put a little YouTube icon
down in the bottom for reference. Here's
what Gemini generated. What I like about
Gemini, though, is that it actually gave
it the proper aspect ratio. But that's
the new model. some examples of what
it's capable of. The free resource that
where you can go and generate it, albeit
not the best way to generate images if
you specifically want to use a model,
but it's the only way we got right now.
And most of the time, it's actually
pretty good at its job. Just head on
over to LM Arena. It helps both the AI
community when you vote on stuff and
also allows you to generate a lot of
stuff for free. As far as when Nano
Banana is available, I'm not quite sure
yet, but I have it on pretty good
authority that we'll get access to it
pretty soon in a much easier to use
interface, one that a lot of people are
already probably using and one that I've
talked a lot about on this channel in
the past. But if you want to get in
early, you want to be on the bleeding
edge and be able to create images and
edit images with pretty much the best
model out there right now, this is how
you can do it before the rest of the
world gets their hands on it. And once
this model gets really, really dialed
in, you're going to be able to do like
almost anything you can do in Photoshop
by just giving a few images and some
text prompts of what you're looking for.
So exciting new tool, exciting new thing
that I wanted to show off and play
around with a little bit and also give
some insight into how you can play with
it as well. So hopefully you found this
helpful. If you like staying up to date
with the latest AI news, the latest AI
tools, and you want tutorials and demos
and that sort of stuff, that's what I do
on this channel. That's my main focus. I
play with all the AI tools. I keep up
with the latest AI news and I turn
around and I share it back with you on
these free videos a couple times a week.
If you like this kind of stuff, make
sure you like this video, subscribe to
this channel. it will make sure more
stuff like this shows up in your YouTube
feed. Thank you so much for hanging out
and nerding out with me today. Really,
really appreciate you. Hopefully, I'll
see you in the next one. Bye-bye. Thank
you so much for nerding out with me
today. If you like videos like this,
make sure to give it a thumbs up and
subscribe to this channel. I'll make
sure more videos like this show up in
your YouTube feed. And if you haven't
already, check out futuretools.io where
I share all the coolest AI tools and all
the latest AI news. And there's an
awesome free newsletter. Thanks again.
Really appreciate you. See you in the
next one.